<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Wangqian Ju&#39;s website</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Wangqian Ju&#39;s website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 22:03:48 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Include C code in R</title>
      <link>/2022/03/31/r-source-c/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 22:03:48 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2022/03/31/r-source-c/</guid>
      <description>Intro This is a short summary of how to add C source code into an R package. I wrote this a year ago as a course material summary (STAT 580) and believed that I would remember all the basic details forever. Obviously, I was wrong. So I’m not 100 percent sure about the following contents and can only hope that this is still helpful to, I don’t know, at least myself in the future :) Enjoy!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to cmpsR package</title>
      <link>/2022/03/31/cmpsr-intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 21:53:59 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2022/03/31/cmpsr-intro/</guid>
      <description>cmpsR  The cmpsR package is an implementation of the Congruent Matching Profile Segments (CMPS) method (Chen et al. 2019). In general, it can be used for objective comparison of striated tool marks, but in our examples, we mainly use it for bullet signatures comparison. The CMPS score is expected to be large if two signatures are similar. So it can also be considered as a feature that measures the similarity of two bullet signatures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 20:26:51 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>My name is Wangqian (Will) Ju, a Ph.D. student in Statistics at Iowa State University, supervised by Dr. Heike Hofmann, and a graduate research assistant at the Center for Statistics and Applications in Forensic Evidence (CSAFE). I received my Bachelor&amp;rsquo;s degree in Statistics from University of California, Davis and my Master&amp;rsquo;s degree in Statistics from Iowa State University.
Research Interest:   Computational statistics
  Graphics and visualization
  Forensic statistics</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resume / CV</title>
      <link>/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 20:26:51 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resume/</guid>
      <description>Resume (2022) Resume
CV (2022) CV</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
